Alaleh Ahmadian

Curriculum Vitae

School of Electrical Engineering and Computer Science Washington State University Pullman, Washington, 99163 alaleh.github.io a.ahmadianshalchi@wsu.edu alaleh.adn@gmail.com

RESEARCH SUMMARY

My general research interests are in Artificial Intelligence (AI), Machine Learning (ML), and Sequential Decision-making under Uncertainty with applications to real-world problems in engineering and scientific domains. My current research focuses on developing fast and effective Bayesian Optimization (BO) methods and applying them to real-world problems to accelerate hardware design and 3D printing of biomedical structures.

EDUCATION

Washington State University, Pullman, WA

Fall 2019 - Present

Doctor of Philosophy in Computer Science

Advisor: Prof. Jana Doppa

Research Topic: Use-Inspired Bayesian Optimization for Science and Engineering Applications

Sharif University of Technology, Tehran, Iran

2019

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science

Research Topic: Design and development of scalable algorithms for graph-matching in large ridesharing networks

Professional Experience

Software Engineer - Machine Learning Intern, Meta (Seattle, WA) May 2024 – Present **Description**: Part of the business compromise protections team.

Research Assistant, Washington State University, EECS

Aug 2019 – Present

Teaching Assistant, Washington State University, EECS

Aug 2019 – Dec 2023

Courses: Big Data, Machine Learning, Advanced Data Structures, Algorithm Design and Analysis

Machine Learning Engineering Intern, Rahnema Co (Tehran, Iran) Dec 2018 – Mar 2019 Description: Played a key role in developing a recommendation system using deep learning methods. Responsibilities included designing and implementing ML models, collaborating with the software development team, and conducting data analysis to identify trends for system improvement.

Teaching Assistant, Sharif University of Technology Fall 2015 – Fall 2018 **Courses:** Introduction To Programming(Java), Design and Analysis of Algorithms, Data Structure Design, Introduction To Programming(C/C++)

Front-End Web Development Intern, Chi Co. (Tehran, Iran) Sept 2016 – Dec 2016 Description: Specialized in Front-End design and development, utilizing HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and Bootstrap frameworks. Played a key role in creating responsive and user-friendly web interfaces, ensuring cross-browser compatibility, and integrating dynamic content for an enhanced UX.

Algorithm Design and Programming Instructor

June 2014 – Sept 2014

National Organization for Development of Exceptional Talents, Farzanegan1, Mashhad, Iran

PUBLICATIONS

- A. Ahmadian, S. Belakaria, and J. Doppa Non-myopic Multi-objective Bayesian Optimization. 38th Annual Conference on Neural Information Processing Systems (NeurIPS), 2024 (Under review).
- A. Ahmadian, S. Belakaria, and J. Doppa Pareto front-Diverse Batch Multi-Objective Bayesian Optimization. The 38th Annual AAAI Conference on Artificial Intelligence (AAAI), 2024.

Alaleh Ahmadian Curriculum Vitae 1 of 3

- A. Ahmadian, S. Belakaria, J. Doppa Preference-Aware Constrained Multi-Objective Bayesian Optimization. 7th Joint International Conference on Data Science & Management of Data (ACM CODS-COMAD), 2024.
- A. Ahmadian, E. Chen, S. Sparks, A. Deshwal, J. Doppa, and K. Qiu Machine Learning Enabled Design and Optimization for 3D-Printing of High-Fidelity Presurgical Organ Models Journal of Advanced Materials Technologies (Under Review)
- S. Belakaria, Z. Zhou, A. Ahmadian, J. Doppa, and D. Heo. Multi-Output Switched-Capacitor Converter Design Optimization via Machine Learning. *IEEE Design and Test of Computers*. (Under review)
- A. Ahmadian, S. Belakaria, J. Doppa Preference-Aware Constrained Multi-Objective Bayesian Optimization for Analog Circuit Design: An Information-Theoretic Approach. Workshop on ML for Systems at Conference on Neural Information Processing Systems (NeurIPS), 2022.
- A. Ahmadian, A. Deshwal, S. Belakaria, C. Simon, and J. Doppa. **Bayesian Optimization for Design of Metal-organic Frameworks.** (In preparation)

SKILLS

- Python(pandas, numpy scipy, pytorch, botorch, scikit-learn), R, SQL, MATLAB, C, C++, Java
- Data Analysis, Data Visualization, Mathematical Modeling, Statistical Modeling, Algorithm Analysis, Data structures, Discrete Mathematics, Graph Theory, Statistics, and Problem-Solving theoretically and practically
- Web development (Django, Python, CSS, HTML, JS, VueJS), LATEX, Linux, Bash, git

ACADEMIC PROJECTS

Design of Multi-Objective Bayesian Optimization Algorithms, Aug 2019 – Present Description: Developing fast and scalable multi-objective Bayesian optimization methods for science and engineering applications.

Machine Learning to Optimize 3D Printing,

Dec 2021 - Dec 2023

Description: Designing a multi-objective Bayesian Optimization method to optimize 3D printing of body parts

Bayesian Optimization to Accelerate Hardware Design,

Aug 2021 – Dec 2022

Description: Designing a robust Multi-Objective Bayesian Optimization method to optimize a high conversion ratio converter's efficiency as well as settling time.

${\bf Bayesian\ Optimization\ for\ Metal-Organic\ Frameworks},$

July 2021 – June 2022

Description: Design a multi-objective Bayesian optimization algorithm to select optimal metalorganic framework (MOF) structures from a library of materials for hydrogen-powered vehicles. Paper to be submitted to Chemistry journal.

Ride-Sharing graph matching,

 $Oct\ 2018-May\ 2019$

Description: Developing a scalable algorithm to find the most efficient matching for a ride-sharing system in a mega city network graph.

Social Network Posts Analysis,

 $Jan\ 2018 - July\ 2018$

2022

Description: Using sentiment analysis to Find the relationship between fake news and its prominent attributes in order to classify news sources that are mostly fake and predict the type of news(fake, true, misleading,...).

AWARDS AND HONORS

Outstanding Graduate Teaching Assistant Award from Voiland College of Engineering Washington State University

Alaleh Ahmadian Curriculum Vitae 2 of 3

Outstanding Graduate Teaching Assistant Award from EECS Department Washington State University

2022

Selected amongst the top 40 people from 1800 candidates through three rounds of exams for Rahnema College ML internship 2018

Ranked in the first 0.5% (791 out of 191,551 participants) in the national university entrance exam (Math and Physics major)

Ranked in the first 0.1% (122 out of 99,104 participants) in the national university entrance exam (English Literature major)

2014

MISCELLANEOUS

Program Committee Member - Reviewer

- International Conference on Learning Representations (ICLR) 2024
- Conference on Neural Information Processing Systems (NeurIPS) WiML workshop 2023
- Association for the Advancement of Artificial Intelligence (AAAI) Conference 2023, 2024
- AAAI Workshop on AI to Accelerate Science and Engineering 2022, 2024
- The International Conference on Automated Planning and Scheduling (ICAPS) 2021
- IEEE Transactions on Systems, Man, and Cybernetics

Technical/Professional Events

- Selected to Participate in Meetings for Professional Growth
 - CRA-WP Graduate Cohort for IDEALS 2024
 - CRA-WP Graduate Cohort for Women 2020, 2021, 2022
- Presentations/Talks
 - AAAI 2024 Student Abstract Program Oral Presentation.
 - SRC TechCon 2022 Presenting our work on "Preference-Aware Bayesian Optimization to Accelerate Hardware Design".
- Volunteer Work
 - AAAI Conference on Artificial Intelligence, 2024
 - Women in Machine Learning (WiML) Workshop, NeurIPS 2022
 - International Conference on Machine Learning (ICML), 2022
 - Women in Machine Learning (WiML) Workshop, NeurIPS 2021

LANGUAGES

• Persian (Native), English (Professional), Arabic (Limited Working Proficiency)

References

• Prof. Jana Doppa

George and Joan Berry Distinguished Associate Professor School of Electrical Engineering and Computer Science Washington State University Email: jana.doppa@wsu.edu

• Prof. Partha Pande

Boeing Centennial Chair Professor School of Electrical Engineering and Computer Science Washington State University Email: pande@wsu.edu